<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Musings on :)</title>
    <link>https://aybdee.xyz/musings/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Musings on :)</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2024 01:00:12 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aybdee.xyz/musings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>On the Past Little while</title>
      <link>https://aybdee.xyz/musings/onthepastlittlewhile/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2024 01:00:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aybdee.xyz/musings/onthepastlittlewhile/</guid>
      <description>The spiritual controls the physical. That&amp;rsquo;s how I, like many others around me, have been brought up to live my life—to see everything through the lens of spirituality. Whether you succeeded or failed, your emotions, whether your life was worth anything, whether you got to live the next second or die right now, all of it was determined by your relationship with God. He was the key, the only thing that mattered.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;The spiritual controls the physical. That&amp;rsquo;s how I, like many others around me, have been brought up to live my life—to see everything through the lens of spirituality. Whether you succeeded or failed, your emotions, whether your life was worth anything, whether you got to live the next second or die right now, all of it was determined by your relationship with God. He was the key, the only thing that mattered. He had all the answers, and all you needed to do was just love and serve Him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a while now, I&amp;rsquo;ve been moving away from all that. In some ways, maybe I was never really fully in it to begin with. It&amp;rsquo;s left me with a lot on my mind&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess the first thing is why, and it&amp;rsquo;s something that becomes more confusing when I think about my background. Why does one person believe and another move away? I think it&amp;rsquo;s more than just facts and logic or what is absolutely true. The information is usually always right there, and there will always be things that are out of our control, but we just have very different ways of making sense of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other thing is how—how I&amp;rsquo;m going to keep doing this? How it feels? It feels kind of lonely, at least for me. The thing is, religion and belief aren&amp;rsquo;t something you just take off and put on Sundays. It&amp;rsquo;s a way you fundamentally view the world, and when everyone around you is spiritual, you instantly become the odd one out. Through the lens of spirituality, they see you for what you are: a pagan. At best, they&amp;rsquo;ll tolerate you, maybe try to convert you every once in a while because maybe there&amp;rsquo;s still hope for you. At worst, they&amp;rsquo;ll cut you off—can&amp;rsquo;t be unequally yoked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn&amp;rsquo;t always have to be that way, though. It&amp;rsquo;s only a problem if anyone knows. Just put your head down, don&amp;rsquo;t say anything weird, and just pretend. That never killed anyone; what&amp;rsquo;s it going to cost you? Well, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure. Not sure why I&amp;rsquo;m even writing this anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe I&amp;rsquo;m writing to understand, to find some sense of clarity amidst the confusion, maybe I&amp;rsquo;m wrting because, in this solitude, I hope someone else feels the same way. Perhaps there&amp;rsquo;s comfort in knowing that we&amp;rsquo;re not alone in our questions, that our struggles with faith, or the lack thereof, are part of the human experience. And perhaps, just maybe, that&amp;rsquo;s enough.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Burn The Future I</title>
      <link>https://aybdee.xyz/musings/burnthefuture/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 01:00:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aybdee.xyz/musings/burnthefuture/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s pretty late, and I&amp;rsquo;m typing on my old tactile switch keyboard while thinking (well, I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking) about my future. I feel like my perspective on my ideal future has changed a lot since I started school (which is crazy, considering it has only been a bit more than two years).
What I first pictured for myself was the life of a successful entrepreneur with lots of control, money, and influence.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s pretty late, and I&amp;rsquo;m typing on my old tactile switch keyboard while thinking (well, I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking) about my future. I feel like my perspective on my ideal future has changed a lot since I started school (which is crazy, considering it has only been a bit more than two years).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I first pictured for myself was the life of a successful entrepreneur with lots of control, money, and influence. All I needed to do was to be extremely good at what I do (which happens to be programming), get a really great job first, and then build a startup that blows up, makes me a lot of money, becomes a big business, and gives me influence. I could do the things I want with maximum freedom and live my life without monetary limits, and so on. I didn&amp;rsquo;t really choose to run a business because it had any specific appeal to me; I mostly chose it because it seemed like the most surefire way to achieve the goals I had in mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what changed? It&amp;rsquo;s challenging to pinpoint exactly. I think the first thing that changed was the feasibility of it all. I started to come to terms with how oddly difficult life could be and how I wasn&amp;rsquo;t as good at some things as I thought I was. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot more that went into this (for instance, how I had serious problems with specialization), but I don&amp;rsquo;t think I have the strength to type all of that out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In retrospect, it seems a little like I gave up and quit on my big dreams. Did I?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other main reason I changed is the more impactful one and, for the most part, why I&amp;rsquo;m writing this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d never really stopped to ask myself what I wanted out of life. Not the cliché stuff like lots of money and lots of freedom (everybody wants that), but the harder questions that have a lot to do with tradeoffs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing is, it&amp;rsquo;s really easy to think about your future through the lens of big, haughty dreams where you get to have it all without any cost (except your conveniently placed hard work). But, in reality, life is full of tradeoffs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so, for better or worse, it was important that I picked mine (or is it important? I&amp;rsquo;m not done picking yet).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the question then is, since I can&amp;rsquo;t have it all, what were the most important things I wanted to have? You should probably note here that I&amp;rsquo;m by no means considering myself incompetent or trying to settle for anything less than the best possible version of my life. I just think it&amp;rsquo;s necessary for me to more clearly understand what I&amp;rsquo;m working toward, and this is a way of establishing my priorities.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr Cow</title>
      <link>https://aybdee.xyz/musings/drcow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 12:46:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aybdee.xyz/musings/drcow/</guid>
      <description>If only I wasn’t in this class
I’d be out on the streets making cash
I’d go on trips above and beyond
With the ones I love, staying out in the sun
But sadly I’m stuck in this room right now
With my least favorite teacher in the world dr cow
Here seconds pass by like they were years
And the distinct murmuring aches my ears
Maybe if I think about a life</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;If only I wasn’t in this class&lt;br&gt;
I’d be out on the streets making cash&lt;br&gt;
I’d go on trips above and beyond&lt;br&gt;
With the ones I love, staying out in the sun&lt;br&gt;
But sadly I’m stuck in this room right now&lt;br&gt;
With my least favorite teacher in the world dr cow&lt;br&gt;
Here seconds pass by like they were years&lt;br&gt;
And the distinct murmuring aches my ears&lt;br&gt;
Maybe if I think about a life&lt;br&gt;
Or decide to end mine with a very sharp knife&lt;br&gt;
I’d at last be saved from harrowing hell&lt;br&gt;
Or at least find an excuse to stay in my cell&lt;br&gt;
Is it just me or does this class drive you mad&lt;br&gt;
It’s probably just the stomach ache making me sad&lt;br&gt;
Well , I guess that’s all for now&lt;br&gt;
Final words for my least favorite teacher Dr Cow&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
