<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>:)</title><link>https://aybdee.xyz/</link><description>Recent content on :)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2024 01:00:12 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aybdee.xyz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>On the Past Little while</title><link>https://aybdee.xyz/musings/onthepastlittlewhile/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2024 01:00:12 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://aybdee.xyz/musings/onthepastlittlewhile/</guid><description>The spiritual controls the physical. That&amp;rsquo;s how I, like many others around me, have been brought up to live my life—to see everything through the lens of spirituality. Whether you succeeded or failed, your emotions, whether your life was worth anything, whether you got to live the next second or die right now, all of it was determined by your relationship with God. He was the key, the only thing that mattered.</description><content>&lt;p>The spiritual controls the physical. That&amp;rsquo;s how I, like many others around me, have been brought up to live my life—to see everything through the lens of spirituality. Whether you succeeded or failed, your emotions, whether your life was worth anything, whether you got to live the next second or die right now, all of it was determined by your relationship with God. He was the key, the only thing that mattered. He had all the answers, and all you needed to do was just love and serve Him.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For a while now, I&amp;rsquo;ve been moving away from all that. In some ways, maybe I was never really fully in it to begin with. It&amp;rsquo;s left me with a lot on my mind&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I guess the first thing is why, and it&amp;rsquo;s something that becomes more confusing when I think about my background. Why does one person believe and another move away? I think it&amp;rsquo;s more than just facts and logic or what is absolutely true. The information is usually always right there, and there will always be things that are out of our control, but we just have very different ways of making sense of it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The other thing is how—how I&amp;rsquo;m going to keep doing this? How it feels? It feels kind of lonely, at least for me. The thing is, religion and belief aren&amp;rsquo;t something you just take off and put on Sundays. It&amp;rsquo;s a way you fundamentally view the world, and when everyone around you is spiritual, you instantly become the odd one out. Through the lens of spirituality, they see you for what you are: a pagan. At best, they&amp;rsquo;ll tolerate you, maybe try to convert you every once in a while because maybe there&amp;rsquo;s still hope for you. At worst, they&amp;rsquo;ll cut you off—can&amp;rsquo;t be unequally yoked.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It doesn&amp;rsquo;t always have to be that way, though. It&amp;rsquo;s only a problem if anyone knows. Just put your head down, don&amp;rsquo;t say anything weird, and just pretend. That never killed anyone; what&amp;rsquo;s it going to cost you? Well, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure. Not sure why I&amp;rsquo;m even writing this anyway.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maybe I&amp;rsquo;m writing to understand, to find some sense of clarity amidst the confusion, maybe I&amp;rsquo;m wrting because, in this solitude, I hope someone else feels the same way. Perhaps there&amp;rsquo;s comfort in knowing that we&amp;rsquo;re not alone in our questions, that our struggles with faith, or the lack thereof, are part of the human experience. And perhaps, just maybe, that&amp;rsquo;s enough.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Talking about GANS</title><link>https://aybdee.xyz/scribbles/gantalking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 10:57:12 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://aybdee.xyz/scribbles/gantalking/</guid><description>think of an intro (something about how you haven&amp;rsquo;t done serious ML in a while and you decided to blitz through some GAN papers - maybe talk about how you want to colour manga using GANS (link to the paper) and how the paper didn&amp;rsquo;t make any sense at first)
Before talking about GANS i think it&amp;rsquo;d be cool to talk about how computer scientists frame the problem of generating (data?</description><content>&lt;p>think of an intro
(something about how you haven&amp;rsquo;t done serious ML in a while and you decided to blitz through some GAN papers - maybe talk about how you want to colour manga using GANS (link to the paper) and how the paper didn&amp;rsquo;t make any sense at first)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before talking about GANS i think it&amp;rsquo;d be cool to talk about how computer scientists frame the problem of generating (data?)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>we look at sample data(thats the patterns we want to generate as probability distributions) across some domain&lt;/p>
&lt;p>if you&amp;rsquo;re not familiar with the term&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ndash; drop wikipedia? definition of probability distributions here&lt;/p>
&lt;p>probability distributions are the way we represent the likelihood that some data sample will occur at a point(in some number space)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>an example with the MNIST dataset(if you&amp;rsquo;ve never heard of it it&amp;rsquo;s a dataset of handwritten digits sized 28x28)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>since each image is 28x28 pixels we&amp;rsquo;ve got 784 (values?) for each image&lt;/p>
&lt;p>say we represent that in a coordinate system with 784 dimensions(this isn&amp;rsquo;t something people really do - if we needed to though we&amp;rsquo;d need to use some sort of dimensionality reduction first)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>we&amp;rsquo;d have 784^(784) possible data points that could occur
but not every data point would be MNIST digits
in fact most of it would be noise&lt;/p>
&lt;p>a probability distribution for MNIST basically gives us a value between 0 and 1 for each data point that represents how likely that point is to be a number, kinda like a description
all I&amp;rsquo;d need to do to (generate)? numbers if i had this distribution
is take the data points with a high probability in the distribution&lt;/p>
&lt;p>so in a way we can think of generating taking points from a probability distribution of the items we&amp;rsquo;re trying to generate (that are not included in the training set that we used to somehow do this)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>ok so we&amp;rsquo;re hopefully up to speed..&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Generative Adversarial Networks work by trying to make a new probability distribution that is as similar as possible to the intrinsic distribution of our training data&lt;/p>
&lt;p>since all the information we have about this &amp;ldquo;intrinsic&amp;rdquo; distribution is its samples(our training data) you can also say GANs try to estimate a probability distribution(think a description for out ) from its observed samples&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Replicating v16 spotify recommendation system</title><link>https://aybdee.xyz/scribbles/v16spotify/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 10:57:12 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://aybdee.xyz/scribbles/v16spotify/</guid><description>the initial model for candidate selection was WRMF(weight regularized matrix factorization)
from the name its pretty easy to assume what it&amp;rsquo;s supposed to be doing
basically matrix factorization as used in regular collaborative filtering problems
where the userxitem ie preferences/ratings or whatever floats your boat is factorized into user and item embeddings that can be used for subsequent predictions
I think the regularization employed here is just for more efficiently learning (something i think is pretty relevant in this case since we&amp;rsquo;ve got like 20k&amp;hellip;.</description><content>&lt;p>the initial model for candidate selection was WRMF(weight regularized matrix factorization)&lt;br>
from the name its pretty easy to assume what it&amp;rsquo;s supposed to be doing&lt;/p>
&lt;p>basically matrix factorization as used in regular collaborative filtering problems&lt;/p>
&lt;p>where the userxitem ie preferences/ratings or whatever floats your boat is factorized into user and item embeddings that can be used for subsequent predictions&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think the regularization employed here is just for more efficiently learning (something i think is pretty relevant in this case since we&amp;rsquo;ve got like 20k&amp;hellip;..)
the creators of v16 link to a paper that more or less describes their specific approach to WRMF
(Collaborative Filtering for Immediate Feedback Datasets)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>it starts by distinguishing what immediate feedback recommendation problems are and the unique challenges that come as a result&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(can&amp;rsquo;t really do the whole thing that would take forever)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>for the most part,Implicit feedback problems occur when there aren&amp;rsquo;t any explicit(for lack of better word) metrics by which users rank the items that they interact with (usually in the form of a star rating or a ranking or something like that)
instead what you have is just the data on how the user interacts with items , so stuff like how many times they bought something or clickedon a product)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>generating recommendations for users from implicit feedback data is significantly different
one because there isn&amp;rsquo;t any way of quantifying negative preference with the data
(in a ranking system a 1 star rating means the user probably dislikes the product but there&amp;rsquo;s no such thing as negatively clicking a lick)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>and then there&amp;rsquo;s also the fact that these kinds of data tend to be more noisy because not all interactions might come from the user
(this is something that is largely mitigated with rating systems because most people ranking and starring products are doing it to show their personal preference in some way and would rarely bother ranking when someone else is involved)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>lastly is just the increase in the overall complexity of the model for solving the problem
with a simple numerical rating the problem is just to predict a specific score and
the metrics for model success are pretty clear
something like root mean square could probably suffice&lt;/p>
&lt;p>with Implicit feedback it&amp;rsquo;s a little different
since we&amp;rsquo;re working with user interactions
the model is predicting the likelihood of the user performing a certain interaction
for all possible interactions&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(that means we&amp;rsquo;ll have to consider things like availability of the item(whether the interaction can even happen in the first place),
competition with other items, and repeat feedback(not quite sure what this is))&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>You Did This</title><link>https://aybdee.xyz/posts/youdidthis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 10:57:12 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://aybdee.xyz/posts/youdidthis/</guid><description>I wish I could remember like it was yesterday, all I really remember are flashes, flashes of the most horrible moments of my life.
I&amp;rsquo;d just finished evening lessons and I had to go back home, it was the same old routine, I&amp;rsquo;d done this for about three years, pick my little sister and take the A11 bus back home .On the way back we&amp;rsquo;d meet Brad, he&amp;rsquo;s this guy from the prep school next to mine that I&amp;rsquo;ve been datin for a while.</description><content>&lt;p>I wish I could remember like it was yesterday, all I really remember are flashes, flashes of the most horrible moments of my life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;d just finished evening lessons and I had to go back home, it was the same old routine, I&amp;rsquo;d done this for about three years, pick my little sister and take the A11 bus back home .On the way back we&amp;rsquo;d meet Brad, he&amp;rsquo;s this guy from the prep school next to mine that I&amp;rsquo;ve been datin
for a while.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He&amp;rsquo;s really nice and I enjoy talking with him. we&amp;rsquo;d get to the crossing and my sister would beg for me to let her cross the road alone because she was 9 now and a big girl and everyday I&amp;rsquo;d say
&amp;ldquo;absolutely not&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That day was different
She does the weird cute eyes thing. I really love those tiny eyes. Brad joins her too. I look at the road and it seems pretty ok, what&amp;rsquo;s the worst that could happen.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I tell her she can go but to be careful and that it was a one-time thing, mom would kill me if she found out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She darts across the road and I instantly realize what&amp;rsquo;s about to happen. I drop my bag and sprint after her, Brad runs after me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I trip and fall
&lt;br>
&lt;br>
&lt;br>
&lt;br>
FLASH
&lt;br>
&lt;br>
&lt;br>
&lt;br>
I think I jammed my knee, I can&amp;rsquo;t get up, I hear the brakes on the truck screech and people around are screaming
&lt;br>
&lt;br>
&lt;br>
&lt;br>
FLASH
&lt;br>
&lt;br>
&lt;br>
&lt;br>
I think the truck just made impact. I hear the soft screeching of human flesh against the tarmac. She probably got caught under the bumper.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Brad runs toward the truck
&lt;br>
&lt;br>
&lt;br>
&lt;br>
FLASH
&lt;br>
&lt;br>
&lt;br>
&lt;br>
I see the blood trail her body leaves, I have to get up, I have to help her, she has to be ok, I try to pry myself up on my other leg but i fall again
&lt;br>
&lt;br>
&lt;br>
&lt;br>
FLASH
&lt;br>
&lt;br>
&lt;br>
&lt;br>
My head hits hard on the road, Brad is back at my side, what is he doing here, why isn&amp;rsquo;t he helping her. I lose consciousness as the effect of the hit starts to sink.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As I slip into the darkness I realize what had just happened, what I&amp;rsquo;d just done&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I had killed my sister&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I wake up on a hospital bed, I must have been out for a few hours. My mother is sitting next to me, her eyes are swollen red, she&amp;rsquo;s definetely
been crying, she holds my hand and says&lt;/p>
&lt;p>it&amp;rsquo;ll be ok. I already know the bad news. my sister was gone, she was gone forever, I&amp;rsquo;d never see her again
&lt;br>
&lt;br>
&lt;br>
&lt;br>
Except she was right there&lt;/p>
&lt;p>standing at the foot of the bed, her clothes were ripped and bloodied from the road, and her left side had been completely mangled.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One arm had been completely severed, and her left eye socket was an
empty, gaping hole. Her skin was covered in deep cuts and abrasions, and dried blood and grime filled the hollows of her face.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She looked at me with her one remaining eye, her face contorted in pain, and said the words that have echoed in my mind ever since: &amp;ldquo;You did this to me.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s been 13 years since then, I&amp;rsquo;m 29 now and my sister still hasn&amp;rsquo;t left, she&amp;rsquo;s always there, standing across from me while I eat, taking the same cab rides as me, sitting on the road at the spot where she
died each time saying the all too familiar words &amp;ldquo;you did this to me&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I wonder why she still bothers with that. I definitely don&amp;rsquo;t need anyone to remind me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I blame myself every day. I wish I&amp;rsquo;d gone instead of her, I wish I didn&amp;rsquo;t listen to Brad. That all doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter now does it?
none of it matters anymore&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been to a few doctors since the incident and I&amp;rsquo;ve been diagnosed with a lot of things, PTSD&amp;rsquo;s at the top of the list, recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve been seeing this therapist who thinks we can work out my problems and that life can go back to &amp;ldquo;normal&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I told her about how my sister keeps me company and she says it would be great if I took meds to help with my &amp;ldquo;hallucinations&amp;rdquo; because &amp;ldquo;getting rid of them is a very important thing for my healing
process&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The thing is, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to feel better, I dont want to forget, I need to remember every day, every second, what I did to her, how I killed her. I can never forget, I must never forget.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s 2:00am in the morning and it&amp;rsquo;s a little chilly, I&amp;rsquo;ve been talking to my sister pretty often for the past few days. She&amp;rsquo;s come up with the perfect plan to make me pay for my actions and today is the
day we we&amp;rsquo;re doing it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve got my rope and the conveniently placed ceiling fan in my
bedroom all ready to go – hanging, how cliche.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Turns out it&amp;rsquo;s actually one of the more painless ways to die, once you&amp;rsquo;ve gotten past all the choking.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I tighten the noose around my neck and the hook of the fan while my sister smiles behind me urging me on, I&amp;rsquo;m glad I can finally make her happy, glad I can finally atone for my sin. I signal to her that I&amp;rsquo;m ready, she nods and kicks the chair under me&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I fall and well&amp;hellip;
you know the rest&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Burn The Future I</title><link>https://aybdee.xyz/musings/burnthefuture/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 01:00:12 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://aybdee.xyz/musings/burnthefuture/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s pretty late, and I&amp;rsquo;m typing on my old tactile switch keyboard while thinking (well, I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking) about my future. I feel like my perspective on my ideal future has changed a lot since I started school (which is crazy, considering it has only been a bit more than two years).
What I first pictured for myself was the life of a successful entrepreneur with lots of control, money, and influence.</description><content>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s pretty late, and I&amp;rsquo;m typing on my old tactile switch keyboard while thinking (well, I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking) about my future. I feel like my perspective on my ideal future has changed a lot since I started school (which is crazy, considering it has only been a bit more than two years).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>What I first pictured for myself was the life of a successful entrepreneur with lots of control, money, and influence. All I needed to do was to be extremely good at what I do (which happens to be programming), get a really great job first, and then build a startup that blows up, makes me a lot of money, becomes a big business, and gives me influence. I could do the things I want with maximum freedom and live my life without monetary limits, and so on. I didn&amp;rsquo;t really choose to run a business because it had any specific appeal to me; I mostly chose it because it seemed like the most surefire way to achieve the goals I had in mind.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So what changed? It&amp;rsquo;s challenging to pinpoint exactly. I think the first thing that changed was the feasibility of it all. I started to come to terms with how oddly difficult life could be and how I wasn&amp;rsquo;t as good at some things as I thought I was. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot more that went into this (for instance, how I had serious problems with specialization), but I don&amp;rsquo;t think I have the strength to type all of that out.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In retrospect, it seems a little like I gave up and quit on my big dreams. Did I?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The other main reason I changed is the more impactful one and, for the most part, why I&amp;rsquo;m writing this.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;d never really stopped to ask myself what I wanted out of life. Not the cliché stuff like lots of money and lots of freedom (everybody wants that), but the harder questions that have a lot to do with tradeoffs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The thing is, it&amp;rsquo;s really easy to think about your future through the lens of big, haughty dreams where you get to have it all without any cost (except your conveniently placed hard work). But, in reality, life is full of tradeoffs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And so, for better or worse, it was important that I picked mine (or is it important? I&amp;rsquo;m not done picking yet).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So the question then is, since I can&amp;rsquo;t have it all, what were the most important things I wanted to have? You should probably note here that I&amp;rsquo;m by no means considering myself incompetent or trying to settle for anything less than the best possible version of my life. I just think it&amp;rsquo;s necessary for me to more clearly understand what I&amp;rsquo;m working toward, and this is a way of establishing my priorities.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Dr Cow</title><link>https://aybdee.xyz/musings/drcow/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 12:46:12 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://aybdee.xyz/musings/drcow/</guid><description>If only I wasn’t in this class
I’d be out on the streets making cash
I’d go on trips above and beyond
With the ones I love, staying out in the sun
But sadly I’m stuck in this room right now
With my least favorite teacher in the world dr cow
Here seconds pass by like they were years
And the distinct murmuring aches my ears
Maybe if I think about a life</description><content>&lt;p>If only I wasn’t in this class&lt;br>
I’d be out on the streets making cash&lt;br>
I’d go on trips above and beyond&lt;br>
With the ones I love, staying out in the sun&lt;br>
But sadly I’m stuck in this room right now&lt;br>
With my least favorite teacher in the world dr cow&lt;br>
Here seconds pass by like they were years&lt;br>
And the distinct murmuring aches my ears&lt;br>
Maybe if I think about a life&lt;br>
Or decide to end mine with a very sharp knife&lt;br>
I’d at last be saved from harrowing hell&lt;br>
Or at least find an excuse to stay in my cell&lt;br>
Is it just me or does this class drive you mad&lt;br>
It’s probably just the stomach ache making me sad&lt;br>
Well , I guess that’s all for now&lt;br>
Final words for my least favorite teacher Dr Cow&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>About me</title><link>https://aybdee.xyz/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://aybdee.xyz/about/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m Abundance, I&amp;rsquo;m a random person (aren&amp;rsquo;t we all) //say something cool about being a programmer
I like knowing stuff and talking about it
also like to solve complex problems
Stuff I know Computers. This probably goes without saying, but i think computers are really cool,
I enjoy learning about how computers work under the hood ( you know, computer architecture and stuff)
I also try to build a few low level projects when i can InshAllah</description><content>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m Abundance, I&amp;rsquo;m a random person (aren&amp;rsquo;t we all) &lt;br>
//say something cool about being a programmer&lt;br>
I like knowing stuff and talking about it&lt;br>
also like to solve complex problems&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="stuff-i-know">Stuff I know&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Computers. This probably goes without saying, but i think computers are really cool,&lt;br>
I enjoy learning about how computers work under the hood (
you know, computer architecture and stuff)&lt;br>
I also try to build a few low level projects when i can InshAllah&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Rust. been learning this for some time, I try implementing some fairly complex projects every once in a while &lt;br>
you should check them out&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Machine Learning. specifically know a lot about deep learning (gotta prepare for our AI overlords)
work mostly with Pytorch(I&amp;rsquo;m pretty good with python)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Know lots of theory about random systems(mostly from &lt;del>failed&lt;/del> developing projects) &lt;br>
notably there&amp;rsquo;s TCP/IP(just network stuff in general), git internals and operating systems&lt;br>
&amp;ndash; this isn&amp;rsquo;t really an exhaustive list&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Web Development - Kinda hate it but it pays i guess, mostly use React or Next for frontend (all in Typescript of course) and Express&lt;br>
FastApi/Flask or django for backend&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h1 id="other-stuff">Other Stuff&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>I read a lot of books on a lot of topics&lt;br>
mostly never finish them (curse my short attention span 😭)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m really into music &lt;br>
like reaaaaaally into music &lt;br>
literally catalog my memories by song &lt;br>
I like mostly pop, 80&amp;rsquo;s, and chill indie stuff &lt;br>
but I&amp;rsquo;ll listen to anything really&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>I dabble in writing every once in a while(mostly when i&amp;rsquo;m really bored)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>interested in cooking(sort of suck at it for now 😫)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h1 id="umm-what-else">umm what else?&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>favourite thing to do &lt;br>
read a book(fiction, alternative reality, mind fucking)&lt;br>
while listening to nice music and feeling happy with my life &lt;br>
not something i do very often tho&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>A pretty close second is sharing fun moments with friends&lt;br>
(i&amp;rsquo;ve got really cool friends)&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>I love to spend money &lt;br>
send me money please 🙂&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h1 id="find-me">Find me&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>on &lt;a href="https://github.com/abundance-io/">Github&lt;/a> please dont judge me 🙈&lt;/li>
&lt;li>on &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/aybdee">Twitter&lt;/a>. I never post :)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Email me &lt;a href="mailto:abundanceanyanwu@gmail.com">abundanceanyanwu@gmail.com&lt;/a>. I&amp;rsquo;ll probably respond in a few years(except you&amp;rsquo;re a potential employer
then consider me responded)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Discord aybdee&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></content></item></channel></rss>