<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>totallynotcrying on :)</title><link>https://abundance-io.github.io/tags/totallynotcrying/</link><description>Recent content in totallynotcrying on :)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 01:00:12 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://abundance-io.github.io/tags/totallynotcrying/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Burn The Future I</title><link>https://abundance-io.github.io/musings/burnthefuture/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 01:00:12 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://abundance-io.github.io/musings/burnthefuture/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s pretty late, i&amp;rsquo;m typing on my old tactile switch keyboard
and thinking(well i&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking) about my future. I feel like my perspective on my ideal future has changed a lot since I got to school (which is crazy considering it has just been a bit more than two years)
what I first pictured for myself was the living-it-big entrepreneur with lots of control, money, and influence, all I needed to do was to be extremely good at what I do (which happens to be programming) get a really great job first then build a startup which blows up, makes me a lot of money, becomes a big business that gives me influence, I get to do the things I want with maximum freedom and live my life without monetary limits, et cetera et cetera.</description><content>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s pretty late, i&amp;rsquo;m typing on my old tactile switch keyboard&lt;br>
and thinking(well i&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking) about my future.
I feel like my perspective on my ideal future has changed a lot since I got to school (which is crazy considering it has just been a bit more than two years)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>what I first pictured for myself was the living-it-big entrepreneur with lots of control, money, and influence, all I needed to do was to be extremely good at what I do (which happens to be programming) get a really great job first then build a startup which blows up, makes me a lot of money, becomes a big business that gives me influence, I get to do the things I want with maximum freedom and live my life without monetary limits, et cetera et cetera. I didn&amp;rsquo;t really pick running a business because it had any specific appeal to me, I mostly picked it because it seemed like the most surefire way to achieve the goals I had in mind&lt;/p>
&lt;p>so what changed
it&amp;rsquo;s really hard to put my finger on, I think the first thing was the feasibility of it all, I started to come to terms with how weirdly difficult life could be and how I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really as good at some things as I thought I was. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot more that went into this (for instance how I had serious problems specializing)
but I don&amp;rsquo;t think i&amp;rsquo;ve got the strength to type all that)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In retrospect, it seems a little like I gave up and quit on my big dreams (did I ?).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The other main reason I changed is the more impactful one and for the most part why I&amp;rsquo;m writing this&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;d never really stopped to ask myself what I wanted out of life&lt;/p>
&lt;p>not the cliche stuff like lots of money and lots of freedom (everybody wants that)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>the harder questions that have a lot to do with tradeoffs&lt;/p>
&lt;p>the thing is, it&amp;rsquo;s really easy to think about your future through the lens of big haughty dreams where you get to have it all without any cost (except your conveniently placed hard work)
but in reality, life is full of tradeoffs&lt;/p>
&lt;p>and so for better or worse, I was important I picked mine(or it is important?? (i&amp;rsquo;m not done picking yet))&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So the question then is
since I can&amp;rsquo;t have it all what were the most important things I wanted to have&lt;/p>
&lt;p>you should probably note here that i&amp;rsquo;m by no means considering myself incompetent or trying to settle for anything less than the best possible version of my life&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I just think it&amp;rsquo;s necessary for me to more clearly understand what i&amp;rsquo;m working towards and this is a way of establishing my priorities.&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>